

DEVILAL GUGULOTH

Panjara hills Road no 12, Hyderabad, Telangana, 500096

盲 +91 9966982326 🐹 <u>devilal.kmm@gmail.com</u> S GUGULOTH DEVILAL

https://www.xing.com/profile/GUGULOTH_DEVILAL/cv

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/devilal-gugloth-661524221/

https://mevihub.com/

PROFILE

I Am a Senior Firmware Engineer With 6 Years Of Experience, Including 2.7 Years Dedicated To The Electric Vehicle (Ev) Automotive Industry. My Expertise Lies In Designing, Developing, And Testing Real-Time Embedded Applications, Specifically Focusing On Ev Control Systems. I Have Proficiency In Hardware And Embedded Design, Incorporating Microprocessor And Microcontroller Interfacing To Meet Client Requirements.

EXPERTISE

Languages : C, C++, Embedded C, Python

• Firmware :TMS320F28379D/F28335/F28069/F280025, PIC33FJ64GS606, PIC16F877ACORTEX-M4, MSP430XX,

LPC2148, Atmega88, Allwinner h3, Raspberry Pi 3

Tools : CCS 11/10/9/8/7, KEIL 4/5, Atollic, STMCubeIDE/MX, MPLAB, QT Creator, ARDUINO, Proteus

Protocols : ISO26262, UART, I2C, SPI, CAN, MQTT, TCP/IP,

Interfacing devices
 : PWM, ADC, GPS, GSM, EEPROM, RTC, IGBT, KEYPAD, DC motor, Relay, LCD IR, GSM, GPS, Wi-Fi,

Bluetooth

Operating Systems : Linux, Windows

EXPERIENCE

Jul 2021 – Mar 2024 Engineer

Sep 2020 – Jul 2021 Senior Firmware Developer

Sep 2019 – Jan 2020 Senior Engineer- Firmware

Jan 2017 – Sep 2019 Software Engineer (Embedded Systems)

HBL Power Systems

Bynark Engineering Pvt Ltd

iLenSys Technologies Pvt Ltd

Unipoint IT Solutions Pvt Ltd

EDUCATION

2017 Masters of Technology Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University, India

(VLSI and Embedded Systems)

2014 Bachelors of Technology Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University, India

(Electronics and Communication Engineering)

KEY PROJECTS

Project # 1 Project Title : 4kW DC-DC Converter
Client : HBL Power Systems

Environment : TMS320F28069S, ADC, CAN, QT Creator.

The 4kw DC/DC converter is a high-performance device that can handle input voltages ranging from 450V to 750V and output a steady 24V at a current rating of 170A. In order to maximize effective power conversion, voltage regulation, and thermal management, this device is crucial.

Responsibilities:

- Taken responsibilities for building and deploying the Application.
- Utilized Qt Creator as the primary development platform, harnessing its features for efficient application development.
- Designing, developing, coding, testing and debugging system software.

Project #2

Project Title : Battery Management Control System(BMCS)

Client : HBL Power Systems Pvt Ltd

Environment : TMS320F28379D, Code Composer Studio (CCS),ADC,CAN,RS232

The battery management system monitor cell voltage, temperature and battery current and then send them to the vehicle control unit. It would have the inbuilt provision of cell balancing during charge mode. It would also communicate with the charger. It would send the parameters and alarms data to the vehicle controller at a regular time interval or event-based.

Responsibilities:

- Involved in requirements analysis, designing, and coding of the application.
- Involved in application development and testing.

Project #3

Project Title : Control of switched reluctance motor drive for electric vehicles (SRM)

Client : HBL Power Systems

Environment : TMS320F28379D, SRM Motor3/6 Phase, Code composer Studio(CCS), AU6805, IGBT

This project mainly focused on the development of Switched reluctance motor (SRM) for Electric Vehicle applications. Control (Speed and Torque) of Traction motors for EV application. In this project we are using a DSP controller to control the SRM motor, to control the SRM motor we are using AU6095 driver and power IGBT, 3 & 6 phase gate driver is used for driving six-pack IGBT power devices.

Responsibilities:

- Understanding base documents and schematics.
- Preparing Design Document.
- Writing code for the MSP430 Microcontroller as per the application requirements.
- Functional Testing as per ATP.

Project #4

Project Title : S1 Pipet Filler

Client : ThermoFisher Scientific (Germany)

Environment : Code Composer Studio (CCS), 1-wire communication, MSP430F413, Lithium-ion

battery, LCD, Motor

The aim of this project is to design a light weight cordless pipet filler which allows longer and fatigue free pipetting. The pipetting speed will be controlled based on motor speed and PWM. The LCD will be interfaced for showing the status of the battery.

Responsibilities:

- Understand client requirements and prepare use case documents.
- Involved in requirements analysis, designing, coding of the application.
- Taken responsibilities for building and deploying the application.

Project #5

Project Title : Centralized Control Monitoring System SMS Gateway

Client : Energy Efficiency Services Limited, New Delhi Environment : H3 ARM Cortex A7 processor, Python, My SQL

Centralized Control Monitoring SMS Gateway System is IOT Gate Way System. It collects data from CCMS box through SMS. This system is designed for old 2G Systems due to the lack of 2G Network. This device receives live data from CCMS system through SMS and pushes it to Main Server. Each gateway supports up to 100 CCMS systems.

Responsibilities:

- Involved in requirements analysis, designing, coding of the application.
- Taken responsibilities for building and deploying the Application.
- Resolved number of Production issues and improved the performance of the application.

PERSONALSKILLS

Mothertongue(s)

Telugu

Other language(s)

iguage(s)	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
English	B1	B1	B1	B1	B1
Hindi	C1	C1	C1	C1	C1
German	A1	A1	A1	A1	A1